<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
  ~ Ktunaxa Referral Management System.
  ~
  ~ Copyright (C) see version control system
  ~
  ~ This program is free software: you can redistribute it and/or modify
  ~ it under the terms of the GNU Affero General Public License as published by
  ~ the Free Software Foundation, either version 3 of the License, or
  ~ (at your option) any later version.
  ~
  ~ This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
  ~ but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
  ~ MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the
  ~ GNU Affero General Public License for more details.
  ~
  ~ You should have received a copy of the GNU Affero General Public License
  ~ along with this program.  If not, see <http://www.gnu.org/licenses/>.
  -->

<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC '-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN'
		'http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd'>
<chapter id="chapter-use-cases">
  <title>Use cases</title>

  <para>This chapter will go over all the use-cases one by one in an attempt
  to describe them as clear as possible.</para>

  <section>
    <title>Use cases - Task management</title>

    <para>Within this paragraph all use-cases related to the referral business
    process are described.</para>

    <section>
      <title>General process information</title>

      <para>There are two processes which are combined in the
      application.</para>

      <para>The main process handles the tasks for the referral manager. It is
      started when a new referral is entered.</para>

      <para>The process starts by a review of the referral. The referral
      manager can correct some of the main fields, including the engagement
      level, completion deadline and the default e-mail address which should
      be used for notifications. You can also indicate if the referral is
      incomplete.</para>

      <para>If the referral manager indicated that the engagement level is 0 ,
      then the process finished by suggesting to send a level 0 notification.
      After that the process ends.</para>

      <para>If the engagement level was non-zero then the process splits in
      two parallel flows (indicated by the plus sign). At the top the
      "evaluate values" sub-process is called to evaluate the Ktunaxa values
      and notify the communities.</para>

      <para>At the bottom the system checks whether the proponent needs to be
      notified of a change. This will happen when either the referral is
      incomplete or when the checkbox to change the referral deadline or
      engagement level was indicated. In that case, a notification is
      (optionally) sent. The next task will then allow setting the agreed
      engagement level and response deadline.</para>

      <para>When everything is agreed on, you can send a notification about
      starting to handle the referral.</para>

      <para>The process then splits based on the engagement level. For all
      levels there is the parallel evaluation of the values. No additional
      work is required for engagement level 1. For engagement level 2 there is
      an option to meet and discuss with the proponent. For level 3 there is
      the meeting train followed by filing the engagement report. At that
      point the user can decide whether the final report needs to be
      produced.</para>

      <para>After the final report, you can indicate in the next task whether
      the concerns which have been reported by KNC are addressed. If this is
      not the case, you can discuss with the proponent and then file the final
      reports.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>General (main) business process</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../../bpm/src/main/resources/diagrams/ReferralHandling.png"
                       width="100%" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para></para>

      <para>The evaluate values block in the main process is handled by the
      evaluate values process.</para>

      <para>In this process the referral manager first determined the values
      to be investigated and the communities which need to be contacted. Then
      for each selected value an evaluator for that value needs to investigate
      the referral. Note the the "auto evaluate..." tasks are place holders
      for possible inclusion of business rules to do some evaluations
      automatically. For each community the community manager needs to inform
      the community and then collect the feedback from the community. The
      process finishes when all selected values and communities have been
      processed.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>Evaluate values business process ("evaluate values" in main
        process)</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../../../bpm/src/main/resources/diagrams/EvaluateValue.png"
                       width="100%" />
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title></title>

      <para></para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Use cases - mapping dashboard</title>

    <para>This paragraph will handle the specific use-cases for the mapping
    dashboard, such as managing document or comments.</para>

    <section>
      <title>Managing layers</title>

      <para>...</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Searching for features</title>

      <para>...</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Printing the map</title>

      <para>...</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Managing comments</title>

      <para>When inspecting the different values in respect to a referral, it
      is possible to attach comments to the referral in question. Nevertheless
      not all comments are regarded as equal, since some of them can be
      attached to the final report, while others are there only to provide
      some extra feedback.</para>

      <para>When entering the comments view, the application will display the
      current list of comments attached to the referral, as seen in the image
      below:</para>

      <para><figure float="0">
          <title>Adding comments to a referral</title>

          <screenshot>
            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="images/mockup/comment_overview.png"
                           format="PNG" width="100%" />
              </imageobject>

              <textobject>
                <phrase></phrase>
              </textobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </screenshot>
        </figure></para>

      <para>In the image above, the list consists of 2 comments. The first one
      has not been added to the report, while the second one is. As a result,
      different options will be available for both.</para>

      <para>As it can be difficult to navigate through large lists, the
      application will allow the user to sort and search/filter within the
      list. Sorting will be possible on the following attributes:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis>Author</emphasis>: The name of the author who wrote
          the original content. This does not have to be the same person who
          added the comment to the report.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis>Date</emphasis>: The time and date when the comment
          was originally created.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para><emphasis>Title</emphasis>: The title of the comment.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>Note also that a button is added to allow the user to add a new
      comment to the referral. By clicking on this button, the user will be
      presented the following view:</para>

      <para><figure float="0">
          <title>Adding a comment to a referral</title>

          <screenshot>
            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="images/mockup/comment_add.png"
                           format="PNG" width="100%" />
              </imageobject>

              <textobject>
                <phrase></phrase>
              </textobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </screenshot>
        </figure></para>

      <para>When creating a new comment, the user has to fill in a title and
      an original content. He immediately has the option to add the comment to
      the report. The second text-area for the report-content will at first be
      disabled. Only when the user actually checks the "add to report" button,
      will this new text-are become available. At that time, the original
      contents will also be copied to the new field.</para>

      <para>If the comments is save, the application will bring the user back
      to the comments list view. From the list view, it is possible to edit an
      existing comment. If the comment has not yet been added to the report,
      the user can do this by clicking the "add to report" button, otherwise
      the user can click the "Edit comment" button. The application will then
      present the following view:</para>

      <para><figure float="0">
          <title>Changing an existing comment</title>

          <screenshot>
            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="images/mockup/comment_edit.png"
                           format="PNG" width="100%" />
              </imageobject>

              <textobject>
                <phrase></phrase>
              </textobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </screenshot>
        </figure></para>

      <para>The original content of a comment can only be changed by the
      original author of that comment. All other users are not allowed to do
      so. What can be changed is the contents that should be added to the
      report.</para>

      <para>If the original author of a comment decides to change the original
      contents, then the process of adding the comment to the report has to be
      done anew.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Managing documents</title>

      <para>...</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>E-mail templates</title>

      <para>When editing e-mail templates, there is a set of fields which
      depends on the e-mail used (mentioned on the edit screen). </para>

      <para>Using a variable can be done using the following two
      constructs:</para>

      <programlisting>${applicantName}


${stopReason!"In progress."}
${externalFileId!""}</programlisting>

      <para>The top construct requires a value to be available. The bottom
      construct contains a default value in case the referral attribute is
      null.</para>

      <para>You can also use the following referral fields:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem><para>fullId</para></listitem>
		<listitem><para>primaryClassificationNumber</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>secondaryClassificationNumber</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>calendarYear</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>number</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>projectName</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>contactEmail</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>provincialAssessmentLevel</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>finalAssessmentLevel</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>responseDeadline</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>responseDate</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>targetReferral</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>documents</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>comments</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>applicantName</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>externalAgencyType</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>externalAgencyName</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>priority</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>projectLocation</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>projectDescription</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>projectBackground</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>finalDisposition</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>applicationType</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>status</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>stopReason</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>decision</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>provincialDecision</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>contactName</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>contactPhone</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>contactAddress</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>type</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>externalProjectId</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>externalFileId</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>activeRetentionPeriod</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>semiActiveRetentionPeriod</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>confidential</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>finalReportIntroduction</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>finalReportConclusion</para></listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
  </section>
</chapter>
